



Faisal Mehmood

Date of birth: 10/02/1996 | **Nationality:** Pakistani | **Gender** Male | (+92) 3123126767 |

faisalmaher979@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/faisal-maher-4829b6132/

Skype: live:.cid.c57fe3a9a38bcfbc

Sialkot, 51310, Sialkot, Pakistan Arfa Software Technology Park Lahore , 54700, Lahore, Pakistan

About me: Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. My expertise are basically in Java and as a backend developer I have worked in different well known companies of my country. I am a confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/12/2020 – CURRENT – Lahore, Pakistan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER – TALLYMARKS CONSULTING

- It's a government project which is having the aims of giving grants to small businesses who got effected by covid-19.
- I am working as Java developer and developing the backend of highly scalable and dynamic application with my team.
- I am responsible for designing the application architecture and writing highly efficient code which fulfills the the clients needs and meets future changes.

01/10/2019 – 30/11/2020 – Islamabad, Pakistan **SOFTWARE ENGINEER** – MICROFINANCE SYSTEMS

- Worked as Java Cloud Developer for banking application which has its foreign clients.
- Create and modify the code to meet client's needs and to increase the application functionality and behavior.
- Optimize the application response time by optimizing the code and database queries.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/08/2014 – 31/12/2019 – Fast NU, Islamabad, Pakistan

BACHELOR OF SCIENCES (COMPUTER SCIENCE) - National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

http://isb.nu.edu.pk/

12/05/2009 – 25/07/2014 – Cadet College Palandri, Azad Jammu and Kashmir, Pakistan **FACULTY OF SCIENCE (FSC)** – Cadet College Palandri AJ&K

http://www.ccp.edu.pk/

DIGITAL SKILLS

Technical Skills

Java 11 | C++ | SQL | NoSQL | JUnit | MySQL | Hibernate | Kafka | RESTful Web Services | JSON | Git | Spring Boot | Maven | Microservices | Swagger | XML | MVC

Tools

Eclipse | SQLyog | Tomcat | MySQL Server | WinScp | Anaconda | Apache Drill | MongoDB | Github Desktop | Visual studio - Visual Basic | Spring Tool Suite 4 | Postman(Basic API tests) | MongoDB compass



Personal Skills

Good listener and communicator | Well-mannered and respectful | Resistance to stress

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): URDU

Other language(s):

| | UNDERSTANDING | | SPEAKING | | WRITING |
|---------|---------------|---------|-------------------|--------------------|---------|
| | Listening | Reading | Spoken production | Spoken interaction | |
| ENGLISH | C2 | C1 | C1 | C2 | C1 |

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user